Irfan Baig

Senior Software Engineer

In my current role, I am a Senior Specialist Engineer having multiple years of API / Web development experience. I work on designing solutions to business problems and delivering in the form of microservices and support for existing and new API services. Passionate developer with 8+ years of experience with a wide range of travel applications and technological skills. I strongly believe I can make a significant contribution to the team.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Engineer

Seera Group / Tajawal | Dubai | 2015 - Present

As a Senior Engineer working in core team. Participate in the design and support of various no of in-house applications. Software development using PHP, JAVA and JavaScript(Node.js). Frameworks like Laravel, Yii2, Node.js, and Spring. Database experience using MongoDB, ElasticSearch and MySQL. Queues using Kafka & rabbitMQ.

- Implementation CI / CD
- Migrating application from PHP to Javascript (node.js) and Java
- Reduced booking failure rates by doing automation
- Migrated to monolith app to microservices
- Desinged json stucture for REST api responses for flights

Sofware Developer

Netiapps Software | Bangalore | 2014 - 2015

SAAS company joined as Software Engineer. Mainly worked on backend techlogies occationaly on the reactive development using Javascript. Software development using Symfony / CMS / Word Press / Drupal / LAMP Stack.

Software Developer

Provab Technosoft | Bangalore | 2013 - 2014

It is a Travelportal as service development company. I worked as Backend Software Developer invovlving integration with various GDS systems like Amadeus / MSC Cruise using SOAP protocol. Software using LAMP Stack.

Software Developer

Startup | Bangalore | 2011 - 2013

Worked as a full stack developer. Developing e-commerce application and school management system. Using LAMP stack and javascript (JQuery).

PROJECTS LINKS

Gold Plus Currency - World Live Prices

Side Project

Build a currency converter and gold price application using flutter. From scratch. On Google store link.



irfan.blackhawk@gmail.com



www.irfanbaigse.info



Dubai



Technical

JavaScript/Angular/React/Vue PHP/Golang/Java

Node.js/Express.js

MongoDB/ElasticSearch/MySQL

Object-oriented design

Laravel/Lumen

Yii2/Codeignitor/Symfony

Docker/AWS

Flutter/App Deployment

System Design/API Design/

REST/XML/SOAP/JSON

Lead and deliver complex software systems

Professional

Effective communication

Energetic

Deadline led

Team player

Quick learner

Team player

EDUCATION

BE in E&C

Visvesvaraya Technological University Karnataka, India 2007 - 2011

LANGUAGES

English (Professional) Urdu / Hindi Kannada (Regional)

INTERESTS

Swimming Cricket Online Gaming Travelling







